MECHANICS:
1. Burst Dash [User3 keybind required, same as in Aetherius]
* A much shorter version of the dash used in Aetherius, which still avoids damage taken from anything while in use.
* You can still dash PAST monsters and projectiles safely as in Aetherius as well, so you can escape being cornered this way.
* Melee attacks from Dinah are still increased in damage if you time them during a dash, though due to the shorter burst time, this is harder to master than in Aetherius.
* [Based off the Dash system from "Hell Crusher" loosely, because it was the first non-ACS coded dash system I found, and I came to like it, thanks to TheCamaleonMaligno for the code base, and H3LLW4LK3R for making Hell Crusher :V]
* Being Berserk'd will allow the dash to deal damage to creatures you dash through or past. Some monsters might even be weak to dashing damage if used right.
* Dashing in mid-air retains your Z-height unless the option is added to change the behavior in a future version.
* Dashing from on the ground will still keep you subject to gravity if going over an edge though, like in Aetherius.
* You do not (usually) start with enough "energy" to do even a single dash, but as you level up, that "energy" eventually hits the point a dash meter appears above your Level stats on the HUD. 
** Usually this will occur somewhere within your first 10 level ups, but takes longer depending on your difficulty.
** Some weapons when equipped [i.e. Hand to Hand, SuperVac, Grimophone] change the "cost" of energy to dash, as does having Berserk active. 
*** If you have enough energy to meet the cost of dashing after these effects when you didn't before, you'll temporarily be able to dash in the mean time, and the meter will show.

2. Health/Hit Points
* Yes, it's RPG-based HP with a dynamically increasing max again, like Aetherius. That said, I plan to have a non-RPG mechanics mode later on that makes Health more "classic" in play, and you'll still have 100 Max Health.
* You don't start with a straight 100 HP, but anywhere from as high as ~102 HP on the Easiest Skill to as low as ~43 on the Hardest skill, averaging ~72 on medium difficulty.
* You do gain experience and level up, but the only "stat" you visibly see going up besides Level, is HP itself, as well as hidden minute boosts to your dash "energy" levels. You always gain at least 1 HP and 1 "dash energy" point per level up.
* RPG mode or not, Dinah can reach THREE-HUNDRED percent of her Max HP at its highest, unlike most protagonists who cap at 200% max HP.
** There is still HP Degeneration above 100% HP though, at about 5 seconds per degen cycle, though in future versions, this will also be made an option.
** Health REGeneration is also still available, though it's slower in base than it is in Aetherius, taking ~20 seconds to regain 1 HP most of the time, unless your health is critically low.
*** Other factors can affect regeneration speed like Aetherius, such as movement, jumping, attack, crouching, defense modes, Berserk buff, etc.

3. Dinah's Stats in General
* Is 50x12 sized instead of the usual 56x16. Yes, that means she can fit in some smaller gaps. <.<;
** Voodoo Dolls should NOT be affected by this and still be 56x16 though for compatibility purposes.
* Does NOT take damagefloor damage when Time is Frozen via Essence of Time potions.
* Takes up to 37.5% less damage from drowning, on the rare occasions you have to deal with underwater.
** When you see "up to x%", it means it's not a consistent resistance, and is up to that level dependent on the RNG, for the record. >.>
* Takes 12.5% more damage from most things. Not exactly Doomguy levels of power at first. :P
* Takes 75% LESS damage from AOE of her own attacks [Cherry Bombs, etc].
* Takes up to 12.5% less damage from AOE of the Cyberdemon's rockets. Not much, but still. V:
* Takes between 25% to 50% less damage from the AOE of the Archvile's Firehex.
* Takes up to 25% less damage from AOE of attacks that are not her own or that of the monsters above.
* Has a fair to strong degree of resistance to REVENANT MISSILES [-37.5 to -87.5% damage taken].
* Is REFLECTIVE when invulnerable now. Also cannot be pushed around by attacks while Invulnerable.
** Invulnerability is not screen-inverted for her, and is a muted violet color now, similar to how the effect is in Aetherius. 
*** Inverted color-screen is OW for the eyes, especially as it wears off. No plz. :V

WEAPONS:
0. All Weapons
* Quick-Kicking/Melee is an option via "User1" keybind, same as in Aetherius.
* This can be done even during the weapon's normal attack animations.

1. Hand To Hand
* New Slot 1 weapon, the unarmed combat "weapon".
* Punches are randomly left or right hooks.
* Alt-fire is an uppercut with slightly less range but more damage.
* Berserk affects both damage [10x, as you expect in Doom, being its exertion based melee], as well as the speed of attacks to an extent.
* When "equipped" with this, you get a bonus boost of ~12.5% to your movement speed and jump height.
** Additionally, you require -3[-4 when berserked] Dash Energy to dash while using Hand to Hand.
** However you additionally take 12.5% more overall damage.

2. Cricket Bat
* Now in Slot 2, and shows up where Pistol/Elven Wands do in gameplay. You still START with it though unless otherwise stated. :V
* Max Ammo increased from 45 to 60. Backpacks set it to 90.
* Holding down the "User4" keybind puts Dinah into a "guard/parry" state with the bat to defend from projectiles [not HITSCANS though] from the front with decent success [moving forward at projectiles increases the chances of being hit right now].
** It also increases her general defense somewhat, and her defense from MELEE greatly (even if she's not hit specfically in the FRONT angle, right now, might tweak it to be less dependant on attacker angle in the future). 
** It will also increase her "mass" by ~50% [i.e. you get shoved/pushed around less by attacks].
** It does slow down her movement speed and lower her jumping strength somewhat however.
** Sometimes projectiles will REFLECT off the bat's guard, but not often.
* Berserk affects attack speed in general with the weapon, as well as multiplies the bonk attack by 10x as you'd expect from berserk via exertion-based melee. 
** Berserk also strengthens the force in hitting Cricket Balls, including their speed, damage on impact, and gives an non-self-damage AOE impact on what it hits.
* Swinging the Bat will also be able to block/reflect projectiles with the right timing, both for melee and ranged modes.
* If you're in melee range when using the alt-fire for a ranged shot, you'll hit the enemy with BOTH the melee and the resulting Cricket Ball at once for extra damage.

3a. BlunderAxe
* Stays in Slot 3, being it's close enough to the Shotgun and Ethereal Crossbow weapons as it is. :P
* Max Ammo increased from 36 to 48. Backpacks set it to 72.
* Spawns usually where the standard Shotgun and Ethereal Crossbow does, but it can also be occasionally replaced by the Scrambler in these spots instead [see below].
* Melee attack is amplified by Berserk [x10 damage] as well as it's swing speed, and even the alt-fire's reload sequence, allowing you to shoot faster at random.
* Lost Souls and Archviles hate being chopped by it. :V
* There is a 1/8[64 for monsters w/ +BOSS] for the chop to induce a defense down buff of -20%, up to two tiers at a max of -40%.
* Killing enemies with the chop often makes them drop more than one Armor Scrap.
* Sometimes an enemy that survives the chop will shed an armor scrap or two.

3b. Scrambler
* Is now in Slot 3, being a sort of SSG-esque weapon. Can occasionally show up instead of the Blunderaxe where the Crossbow in Heretic spwns.
* Max Ammo increased from 20 to 28. Backpacks set it to 42.
* Melee attack is amplified by Berserk [x10 damage] as well as it's swing speed.
** The velocity and impact-damage of Fractal eggs are also increased by Berserk, though smaller eggs are less affected than the main shot, due to how they split on impact.
* There is a 1/4[16 for monsters w/ +BOSS] chance for the Pan's Whack to "confuse" its target, making it fearful, and temporarily changes these flags on the target until it wears off:
** NOINFIGHTING = off
** QUICKTORETALIATE = off
** MISSILEMORE = off
** MISSILEEVENMORE = off
** DONTHARMSPECIES = off
** DONTHARMCLASS = off
** HARMFRIENDS = on
** DOHARMSPECIES = on
** FRIGHTENED = on
** If the actor has the "NOFEAR" flag though, it is immune to being "confused".

4. AppleJack
* Is now in Slot 4, being a Chaingun/Dragon-Claw-ish weapon? :V
* Max Ammo increased from 48 to 64. Backpacks set it to 96.
* The swing still hits two times in one motion.
* Melee attack is amplified by Berserk [x10 damage] as well as it's swing speed, both for melee and for tossing Aggro-Apples.
** The velocity and impact-damage of Aggro-Apples are also increased by Berserk, and they have some non-self-damage AOE on impact.
* Like with the Cricket Bat, you can occasionally block/reflect/destroy projectiles with well timed swings of the melee. This does not apply to the range attack however.

5. Wizard's Pike
* Slot 5. Being it's a rocket launcher/ phoenix rod analogue. :P
* Max Ammo increased from 10 to 12. Backpacks set it to 18.
* Melee attack is amplified by Berserk [x10 damage] as well as it's poking speed.

6. SuperVac
* Slot 6. Even though it mostly functions more like a chainsaw, it's a rapid attack ala the Plasma Rifle/Hellstaff. >.>
* Max Ammo increased from 12 to 16. Backpacks set it to 24.
* Alt-Fire requires at least 8 bags. At max this means THREE charges can be held at once.
* Berserk SLIGHTLY increases the melee/suck attack damage by ~25%. No effect on attack speeds.
* Thanks to the magic of ZScript and EventHandlers, the SuperVac can suck up and erase basically any monsters it kills.
** That said, each enemy has a certain "value" to add to a "bag" for the SuperVac's ammo when deleted. It no longer gives a guaranteed bag per kill. The spawnhealth of a monster is the base factor in how many "units" fill a bag, but it's not a flat value. 
** Though depending on what monster packs you're dealing with, this runs the risk for VM Aborts, as a playtester as mentioned.
** A_BossDeath is called on the monster before it's deleted though, so those special tagged triggers like on E1M8, MAP07, etc. should still work fine. \ :V /
* Lost Souls and Pain Elementals HATE the SuperVac. It deletes the former almost instantly, and greatly halts the latter, as it should. :V
* However many very bulky and large [not necessarily "buff"] monsters, like Cacodemons and Mancubi not only resist the damage, but flinch much less often than from other attacks. Cacos in particular can get off a good number of bites on you if you're unlucky.
* The dust-devil alt-fire attack now bounces off walls a few times before vanishing.

7. Grimphone
* Slot 7. Not exactly a true "BFG" tier weapon, though it IS probably still much more viable than the Firemace in Heretic. :P
* Max Ammo increased from 50 to 66. Backpacks set it to 99.
* Shots have better homing.
* Alt-fire mode is added: the Grimophone will play music and damage anything within 1024 units of Dinah via an A_Explode effect.
** This doesn't (usually) deal self-damage most of the time, however as you hold down the alt-fire longer without letting up, Dinah incurs a temporary debuff making her more vulnerable to damage from non-music sources, which gets worse up to four total tiers. Releasing the alt-fire causes this to vanish though.
* The Grimophone is heavy too, Dinah's speed and jump height, as well as dash length, is noticibly decreased while equipping it.


ITEMS:
1. Berserk Pack/Sphere [spheres appear in Raven gamemode as a potential replacement for certain artifacts]
* Probably a critical powerup for Dinah due to most of her weapons being exertion-based melee for their primary attack [except the SuperVac], besides the Grimophone.
* Lasts 150 seconds per pickup, and carries across level exits.
** All of these get their damage multiplied by 10x, except the SuperVac's suck attack, which is only increased by ~25%.

2. Apple Wine
* Max increased from 8 to 16.
* Heals 18-22% health now instead of a flat 20%, or if you're at/above 100% HP, it gives 4-6% overhealth.
* Using one will also imbue Dinah with a defensive buff that starts at -18.75% damage taken, but can be layered to FOUR levels [or -75% damage taken]. 
** This buff will slow her down and reduces her jump strength at higher levels, but it also lasts longer [5/7/9/12 seconds respectively].
** You also cannot drink any more Apple Wine while your buff is tier 4, and must allow the buff to wear off first.
* Does not empty out to 1 unit in Heretic mode during exits anymore.

3. Cherry Bomb
* Max increased from 12 to 24.
* Damages on EACH frame, ala Blood's Dynamite and Aetherius's Rockbomb Shards. Not nearly as borked as the latter though.
* Berserk affects the throw power AND the impact damage, being it's thrown via exertion, same as Rockbomb Shards in Aetherius are.
* Does not empty out to 1 unit in Heretic mode during exits anymore.

4. Bottle Rocket
* Max increased from 2 to 4.
* Does not empty out to 1 unit in Heretic mode during exits anymore.

5. Spinner
* Max increased from 8 to 16.
* Does not empty out to 1 unit in Heretic mode during exits anymore.

6. Popper
* Max increased from 1 to 2.
* Does not empty out to 1 unit in Heretic mode during exits anymore.

7. King Sugar Snake
* Max increased from 1 to 2.
* Does not empty out to 1 unit in Heretic mode during exits anymore.

8. Essence of Time [Time Potion]
* Can now drop randomly from slain enemies as part of their general drop tables.
* Max of 3, instead of 1.
* Gives 8 to 10 seconds of time freeze, can be stacked.
* Time Freeze uses a similar "effect" as Aetherius, where you can hear ticking clocks and your character's heartbeat.
* Does not empty out to 1 unit in Heretic mode during exits anymore.

9. Chic Diving Helm
* Max increased from 1 to 2.
* Does not empty out to 1 unit in Heretic mode during exits anymore.

10. Bell
* Very rare drop from slain enemies as part of their general drop tables.
* Basically instant-exits the level you're in when used, almost always going to the next NORMAL level if used in a map with a secret exit.
* Can only carry 1 at a time.
* Does not empty out to 1 unit in Heretic mode during exits anymore.

MONSTER CHANGES:
0. General
* If a monster is weaker/resistant to something, it means [usually] both damage taken AND the chance to be flinched by the attack is equally altered.

1. Zombies
* Take 50% more damage from Cherry Bombs and 100% more damage from Fire in general.
* Take 25% more damage from the Blunderaxe's chop attack.

2. Imps
* Not a fan of being chopped by the Blunderaxe.
* Resistant as Hell against fire and Cherry Bombs.

3. Pinky Demons/Spectres
* Give them some Fractal Eggs. :V
* Somewhat resistant to the SuperVac.
* Slightly resistant to Cherry Bombs.
* Fairly resistant to the BlunderAxe's chop attack.
* Spectres have the same resistances/weaknesses.

4. Lost Souls
* USE THE SUPERVAC LUL. :V
** Seriously though, they take obscene damage from the suck attack, and are almost always one-shot by it.
** Also it's just hilarious to see them get erased by it. :P
* They also tend to not like being axe'd questions by the BlunderAxe's chop attack.
* Don't rely on the BlunderAxe's RANGED FIRE however. They resist it. >.>

5. Cacodemons
* Their melee has a sound again, like in Aetherius.
* Feed them some fractal eggs via the Scrambler. They go down FAST from them.
* Conversely, using the SuperVac on them, while decent in an emergency, is not recommended, since their melee range is larger, and they greatly resist it [including their chance to flinch from it.
* Bottle Rockets and Spinners also do nicely against them.
* Cherry Bombs, Poppers and Fire attacks conversely, don't do as well, but still deal some damage.

6. Pain Elementals
* It's base Painchance is SIGNIFICANTLY reduced [to 16/256 from 128/256]. If it's an embodiment of pain, it's safe to say YOUR sources of pain against them are less likely to flinch it.
* Also doesn't like your SuperVac, though it doesn't instantly die to it's suck attack like its Lost Souls do.
* Like in Aetherius, it can now bite in melee to stop you from "hugging" it out of spawning Lost Souls, though using the SuperVac should prevent it from ever doing so [120/256 Painchance, almost what it's BASE painchance used to be]. :P

7. Revenants
* ?

8. Arachnotrons
* ?

9. Barons of Hell / Hell Knights
* HATES your explosive items.
* Partially resistant against the SuperVac's suck attack.

10. Mancubi
* Bonk them with the Cricket Bat in melee if possible.
* Do not rely on Cricket Balls from range though, they take half damage from those.
* They also HATE being chopped by the Blunderaxe.
* They also take extra damage from Blundershot, but not too much.
* They are resistant to the SuperVac's melee.
* But they don't like the Dust Devil alt-fire of the SuperVac.
* Most of your explosive inventory items deal some degree of extra damage to them, Cherry Bombs and Spinners being best if available.

11. Archviles
* Absolutely detests being chopped by the Blunderaxe.
* Not fond of its Blundershot attack either.
* Doesn't like being bonked by the Cricket Bat.
* Also hates being whacked by Cricket Balls from the Bat itself.
* Is also not a big fan of the SuperVac.
* Gives next to no craps about your Cherry Bombs though on the flipside.

12. Spider Masterminds
* EXTREMELY resistant to the SuperVac's melee.
* Also pretty resistant to Cherry Bombs.
* Spinners, Poppers and Bottle Rockets however are in order, more and more effective on them, though they still won't deal AOE damage.

13. Cyberdemons
* EXTREMELY resistant to the SuperVac's melee.
* Also pretty resistant to Cherry Bombs.
* Spinners, Poppers and Bottle Rockets however are in order, more and more effective on them, though they still won't deal AOE damage.

NEW MONSTERS:
1. ?????????? ???????
* Is a super-tough new "leader" variant of an existing enemy from the DD games.
* Good luck is all I say if you spawn them in [they aren't accessible outside of the summon command in the console at the moment]. :V